Discover a place that will never leave you, and a
friendship that will change you forever.
Bridge to Terabithia is a adventure, drama, family film directed by Gábor Csupó.
Jesse Aarons trained all summer to become the fastest runner in school.
So he's very upset when newcomer Leslie Burke outruns him and everyone else.
Despite this and other differences including that she's rich, he's poor, she's a
city girl, and he's a country boy the two become fast friends.
Together they create Terabithia, a land of monsters, trolls,
ogres, and giants where they rule as king and queen.
Jess Aarons, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Leslie Burke, played by AnnaSophia Robb.
Ms. Edmunds, played by Zooey Deschanel.
Jack Aarons, played by Robert Patrick.
May Belle Aarons, played by Bailee Madison.
Mary Aarons, played by Kate Butler.
Bridge to Terabithia is a 2007 American fantasy drama film directed by Gábor
Csupó (in his directorial debut) from a screenplay by David L.
Paterson and Jeff Stockwell.
It is based on the 1977 novel of the same name by Katherine Paterson and stars Josh
Hutcherson, AnnaSophia Robb, Zooey Deschanel, and Robert Patrick.
In the film, adolescent children Jess Aarons (Hutcherson) and Leslie Burke (Robb) create "Terabithia", a fantasy
world, which they use to cope with their troubled reality and spend their free time together.
The original novel was based on events from the childhood of Paterson's son, who went on to write the film's
screenplay; Csupó was hired in late 2005, and the rest of the main cast was rounded out soon after.
Principal photography began in February 2006 and lasted
until that April, taking place in Auckland.
This was the last film for 71-year-old cinematographer Michael Chapman, who
followed through with his planned retirement thereafter.
Bridge to Terabithia was released in the United States on
February 16, 2007, by Buena Vista Pictures.
It received positive reviews from critics, with praise for its visuals,
cast performances, and faithfulness to the source material.
The film grossed $137.6 million worldwide.
At the 29th Young Artist Awards, the film won all
five awards for which it was nominated.
The film explores themes of friendship, sibling
relationship, bullying, neighbor, school.
The tone is emotional.